Guide to the William Manchester Papers, 1934 - 2004
William Manchester Papers1934 - 2004
- Series IX: Media
  - Video
    - Cineworld tape: American Caesar, Episode #1, Cutting copy and rough cut, 3/4" U-matic, 1983 Mar 15 (Box 452)
    - Cineworld tape: American Caesar, Episode #1, Time: 48:00 mins. Original copy, 3/4" U-matic (Box 452)
    - Cineworld tape: American Caesar - Episode #2 The Green Hell, 48:20 minutes, Prod. #7221 COPY, 3/4" U-matic (Box 452)
    - Cineworld tape: American Caesar Episode #3 cutting copy and rough cut, 3/4" U-matic, 1983 Mar 8 (Box 452)
    - Cineworld tape: American Caesar Episode #4 The Last Shogun, F.C.C Version 48 min. 20 sec., 3/4" U-matic (Box 452)
    - Cineworld tape: American Caesar Episode #5, Cutting copy and rough cut, 3/4" U-matic, 1983 Mar 15 (Box 452)
    - Scotch UCA60 Videocassette: Close Up, American Inquisition (Box 452)
    - MBU 18s Master Broadcast Videocassette, Color Plus: DuB Part 2 - JFK Remembered. aired 11/8/83 (Box 452)
- Series X: Realia
  - 4 velvet containers for jewelry (Box 455)
  - Flannel for cleaning Rolex watch (Box 455)
  - 2 small, empty blue boxes with Gerald Ford's signature embossed (Box 455)
  - Button: The Butterfield Colleges, September 18, 1971, 1971 Sep 18 (Box 455)
  - Button: LBC.261 from London, 1966-80 folder (Box 455)
  - Francis Chichester's London Man (Box 455)
  - Pocket calendar, 1995 (Box 455)
  - Envelope: "ofc door" containing placecards (Box 455)
  - Assorted ribbons: black/gold, crimson/white (Box 455)
  - Purple Heart ribbon in small cassette case (Box 455)
  - 4 nametags: 2, UMass Commencement 1965 guest, 2, William Manchester, Professor of History, Emeritus (Box 455)
  - Small nameplate: W. Manchester (Box 455)
  - Bookmark: Olin Memorial Library, Wesleyan University, 1986 Sep 13 (Box 455)
  - 6th Marine Division: assorted stickers, patch and pin (Box 455)
  - Patch: Kennedy Library (Box 455)
  - 2 small orange notepads: Action This Day (Box 455)
  - Brass printer's rule (Box 455)
  - Small clay figure of a head (Box 455)
  - Small brass bell (Box 455)
  - Set of magnets (Box 455)
  - Tiny key: Presto (Box 456)
  - Brass combination lock: Master, Milwaukee No. 175 (Box 456)
  - Small envelope: Extra car keys, (don't fit well) (Box 456)
  - Small envelope: Manchester, William 56260 Fellow-Assoc PC. Key and passcard (Box 456)
  - Archives Key, 1965 Jul 3 (Box 456)
  - Large yellow envelope: Keys (Box 456)
  - Small torn envelope: Keys?, (Olin?) (Box 456)
  - Small yellow envelope: Small key (?) (Box 456)
  - Blue drawstring bag labeled Manchester containing 2 keyrings, 2 keys (Box 456)
  - Several hundred wallet-size items, credit cards, notes, business cards etc. (Box 457)
  - 3 leather wallets: William Manchester (Box 457)
  - Blank checks: Hartford National Bank; Connecticut National Bank (Box 457)
  - Black leather passport case: W.M. (Box 457)
  - Buttons: 3, I [heart] NY, from Corning, 1978 Sep 13-15 (Box 458)
  - Bumper sticker: Kennedy for president (Box 458)
  - Button: John F. Kennedy for president (Box 458)
  - Button: LBJ for the USA (Box 458)
  - Sign: Sorry, this seat is occupied. Eastern Airlines (Box 458)
  - Sealed white envelope: Royal tab stops (Box 458)
  - Luggage tag: BOAC, first class. Manchester, New York, flight 505 (Box 458)
  - Japanese flag, [silk] (Box 458)
  - Package of Dill's pipe cleaners (Box 458)
  - Green, marbled box with assorted hardware (Box 458)
  - 2 address files: Bates list finder and unlabeled (Box 458)
  - 2, day calendars, 1965, 1966 (Box 458)
  - Manilla envelope: USMC chevrons and patches (Box 458)
  - Manilla envelope: Harvard Club of Boston (Box 458)
  - 2 zippered pouches, synthetic leather (Box 458)
  - Copper relief image of John Fitzgerald Kennedy on wooden backing (Box 458)
  - Resolution, City of Chicago condolences to Manchester family on death of William Manchester, 2004 Jun 23 (Box 458)
  - 2" cubic, lucite paper weight with U.S. coins (Box 459)
  - 1.5" cubic, granite paper weight: Deer Isle Granite, Stonington, Maine (Box 459)
  - 3" round, lucite paper weight with quote from RFK, 1968 (Box 459)
  - Green marble paper weight: The New York Times Literary Brunch. Thank you William Manchester, 1988 Sep 18 (Box 459)
  - Glass paper weight from the New York Public Library: William Manchester, Literary Lion, 1983 Nov 8 (Box 459)
  - Lucite paper weight from V-J Day Commemorative Dinner, 1995 Aug 8 (Box 459)
  - Lucite paper weight: The Stanvac Bombay Refinery Dedicated to the Service of the People of India, 1953 Jun 5 (Box 459)
  - Medal on orange ribbon: The New York Public Library, Literary Lions 10th Anniversary (Box 459)
  - Gold-colored metal lions head on crimson ribbon (Box 459)
  - Medal in black plastic weighted stand: Blenheim Award, International Churchill Society in appreciation, William Manchester, 1986 (Box 459)
  - Clock in metal case on black base: Standish, Ayer & Wood, Inc. 60th Anniversary, 1933-93 (Box 459)
  - Medal: 3rd Marine Division, USMC, presented by B. Gen. W.H. Rice. USMC (Box 459)
  - Medal in case, from Saint Nicholas Society, Literary Excellence: Awarded to William Manchester in New York City, 1988 Dec 6 (Box 459)
  - Medal in case, Lincoln Literary Award; The Union League Club, New York to William Manchester, 1983 (Box 459)
  - Medal in case, The Fredrick S. Troy Medal, University of Massachusetts: William Manchester, Arts, 1981 (Box 459)
  - Medal in case, The Sarah Josepha Hale Award: Presented to William Manchester by the Trustees of the Richards Free Library, Newport, NH, 1993 Oct 16 (Box 459)
  - Medal in case, University of Missouri School of Journalism: Awarded to William Manchester for Distinguished Service in Journalism (Box 459)
  - Metal relief disc with unicorn, 3" (Box 459)
  - Press authorization to accept collect radio press messages: William Manchester, All Eouropean and oriental points. In wooden frame (Box 459)
  - Clip on tag: World War II Pacific Theater Veteran (Box 459)
  - U.S. Marines cap (Box 460)
  - Black beret (Box 460)
  - Manilla envelope labeled Class numerals 1944 (Box 460)
  - 2 riding crops (Box 460)
  - Wooden plaque: U.S. Marines (Box 460)
  - Leather passport case (Box 460)
  - Leather notebook case (Box 460)
  - Leather briefcase (Box 461)
  - Award plaque: Marine Corps Combat Correspondents Association. William Manchester - For outstanding service in telling the story of the U.S. Marine Corps to the American people., 1979 (Box 461)
  - Pith helmet (Box 462)
  - World War I, German helmet (Box 463)
  - Academic robes (Box 464)
  - 5, ceramic pencil holders (Box 465)
  - 10" pewter bowl: 1985 Distinguished Public Service Award, Presented to William Manchester by the Connecticut Bar Association, 1985 May 21 (Box 465)
  - 8" metal bowl: William Manchester Award for Excellence in Journalism, established 1976. Brockton High School, Brockton, Massachusetts (Box 465)
  - 3" pewter bowl: Miller & Rhoads Book and Author Dinner, 1976 (Box 465)
  - Metal pencil holder, 4", honeycomb pattern (Box 465)
  - Glass beer mug: University of Massachusetts class of 1946 25th reunion, 1971 Jun 5 (Box 465)
  - Glass tumbler, etched: The only thing we have to fear is fear itself FDR (Box 465)
  - Brass glasses holder, weighted base, lined with red felt (Box 465)
  - Brass message holder, 8" paper clip shape (Box 465)
  - Black metal plate: Friedrich Krupp, Alfried Krupp von Bohlen und Halbach, 1811-1961 (Box 466)
  - Metal plate: Buckeye Incubator Co., Springfield Ohio (Box 466)
  - Metal object, 9"x3" (Box 466)
  - Metal base: 26.100 lb, Krupp.13 (Box 466)
  - Aluminum model of site of President J.F. Kennedy assassination, 11-22-63, 2 pieces (Box 466)
  - Bust of Winston Churchill, 5" high, brown (Box 466)
  - Bust of Winston Churchill, white: Presented to William Manchester for Outstanding Literary Achievement, 1995 (Box 466)
  - Webster's Collegiate Dictionary, 5th edition, 1941 Feb 2 (Box 466)
  - Items removed from frames
    - Awards (Box 467, Folder 1)
    - The Death of a President (Box 467, Folder 2)
    - Honorary degrees (Box 467, Folder 3)
    - Quotations (Box 467, Folder 4)
  - Framed items
    - Photograph of H.L. Mencken, framed with letter from him to W.M. (Box 468)
    - Photograph of Adlai Stevenson and W.M., inscribed by A. Stevenson (Box 468)
    - Image of U.S. Marines raising flag at Iwo Jima. Correspondence pasted to back of framed item (Box 468)
    - Dag Hammarskjoeld award, 1966-67 (Box 469)
    - Book cover: The Glory and the Dream (Box 469)
    - Book cover: The Death of a President (Box 469)
    - Book cover: The Arms of Krupp (Box 469)
  - A Part of the Manchester Family in the 20th Century. 5 Manchester Marines, framed and matted (Box shelf)
  - Typewriters, 3 (Box shelf)